<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>张时中</title>
    <link>http://blog.zhang.today/</link>
    <description>Recent content on 张时中</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2008–2018, Steve Francia and the Hugo Authors; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://blog.zhang.today/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About Hugo</title>
      <link>http://blog.zhang.today/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.zhang.today/about/</guid>
      <description>君子之中庸也,君子而时中，未有知而不行者，知而不行只是未知，如好好色，如恶恶臭。穷极天理要从心上求，心外无物，此运通达，此心光明。
新开一个博客，内容主要想写两方面：  对古代哲学的所想所习 对计算机技术的理解  力求用最简单的语言，描述清楚各知识点的由来、发展、现状和使用。 （内容仅为自己感悟，请谨慎参考。发表只为让更多人不要把时间浪费在找google上，只看这里就够了。）
什么是知识？ 维基百科上，知识就是经由前人的经验累积形成的。 我理解的知识就是人们对事物的认识，研究多就认识深，研究少就认识浅。比如我们看到下雨就知道打伞，其实也是知识的一种，只是比较简单。代码也一样，只不过就是前人的经验积累，一切技术的概念都是水到渠成而来，因此，学习代码并不难，反而跟吃饭喝水一样顺理成章，之所以我们有时候觉得难，很多时候是因为顺序搞错了，这样就产生了信息差。
从计算机的技术的角度讲，无非多是从两方面发展
 从理论到实践 有空再填 从实践到理论，比如，Internet网络，七层架构，五层架构等等都是从实践从慢慢演化而来的（想具体了解，可以看黑皮书 计算机网络），才形成了我们今天的计算机网络理论体系。如果我们在学习的过程中，看到网络层，老去想为什么这样设计？难道不可以那样设计吗？答案当然是可以的（只不过你设计出来可能没法跟其他网络兼容）。那为什么就形成了今天我们看到的设计呢？其实开始设计的时候并没有这样一个指导性的理论体系，这就是一个典型的从实践到理论的过程，之所以这么设计是因为开始的时候并没有完善的体系，前人在不断实践中，比如，网络层和传输层混在一起了，觉得不好耦合性太高，那就分开试试，这样慢慢地才形成了如今的计算机网络，才得出了这么一套理论体系。  有些东西是先出理论，再出应用，有些东西是在应用中，总结出一套理论体系。同时实践和理论又在发展中不断交融。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a New Theme</title>
      <link>http://blog.zhang.today/post/creating-a-new-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.zhang.today/post/creating-a-new-theme/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This tutorial will show you how to create a simple theme in Hugo. I assume that you are familiar with HTML, the bash command line, and that you are comfortable using Markdown to format content. I&amp;rsquo;ll explain how Hugo uses templates and how you can organize your templates to create a theme. I won&amp;rsquo;t cover using CSS to style your theme.
We&amp;rsquo;ll start with creating a new site with a very basic template.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>(Hu)go Template Primer</title>
      <link>http://blog.zhang.today/post/goisforlovers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.zhang.today/post/goisforlovers/</guid>
      <description>Hugo uses the excellent Go html/template library for its template engine. It is an extremely lightweight engine that provides a very small amount of logic. In our experience that it is just the right amount of logic to be able to create a good static website. If you have used other template systems from different languages or frameworks you will find a lot of similarities in Go templates.
This document is a brief primer on using Go templates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Hugo</title>
      <link>http://blog.zhang.today/post/hugoisforlovers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.zhang.today/post/hugoisforlovers/</guid>
      <description>Step 1. Install Hugo Go to Hugo releases and download the appropriate version for your OS and architecture.
Save it somewhere specific as we will be using it in the next step.
More complete instructions are available at Install Hugo
Step 2. Build the Docs Hugo has its own example site which happens to also be the documentation site you are reading right now.
Follow the following steps:
 Clone the Hugo repository Go into the repo Run hugo in server mode and build the docs Open your browser to http://localhost:1313  Corresponding pseudo commands:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrate to Hugo from Jekyll</title>
      <link>http://blog.zhang.today/post/migrate-from-jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.zhang.today/post/migrate-from-jekyll/</guid>
      <description>Move static content to static Jekyll has a rule that any directory not starting with _ will be copied as-is to the _site output. Hugo keeps all static content under static. You should therefore move it all there. With Jekyll, something that looked like
▾ &amp;lt;root&amp;gt;/ ▾ images/ logo.png  should become
▾ &amp;lt;root&amp;gt;/ ▾ static/ ▾ images/ logo.png  Additionally, you&amp;rsquo;ll want any files that should reside at the root (such as CNAME) to be moved to static.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>